# **Megan Paquin:**

**Phone Number:** 802-304-3654 **Email:** megan.j.paquin@gmail.com

#### Overview:

I am a seasoned Project Manager striving to become a Software Engineer. Recently graduated a program learning Full Stack Web Development. I have a passion for solving problems and my engineering background has led me to an immense interest in programming. I have significant experience in technical fields which gives me extensive skills that are applicable to this new adventure.

### **Work Experience:**

#### San Diego University, Student

May 2022 - December 2022

- Worked with Asynchronous HTTP requests for accessing databases to ensure proper data transfer before continuing script. Used this to GET a large catalog of documents from a database to populate a catalog with images, descriptions, prices, ids, etc.
- Create AJAX functions with built in browser XML functions to allow asynchronous operations without reloading the page. Used this method to POST a user order to a database and then GET all orders from that same user to display in a users order tab.
- Developed a REACT web application for an E-commerce site and a supporting database created within MongoDB.
- Created a user friendly front-end design to capture form data and stored in global context states to share data between REACT components.
- This web store included functionality of administrator access, adding products to the database, deleting from the database, data request for all orders, admin access to update order status, user login management, user payment management, user display their previous orders, add items and remove items from a cart.
- Utilized enhanced understanding of algorithms and functions to retrieve users from database and verify user login information before allowing access to page components.
- Utilized react-router-dom package to create a single page web application which enhanced load speed and delivered a cleaner user experience.
- Developed a FLASK web application that utilized jinja2 to build a front-end framework within a python application.

## United States Army: Project Manager, Engineer Officer

December 2013 - PRESENT

- Utilized excellent written and verbal communication skills to create a yearly training calendar that was easy to interpret and understand and was clear and concise.
- Seamlessly interacted with cross-functional teams having highly diverse backgrounds and skills to ensure project deliverables were on-time, on-budget, high-quality, and met the desired outcomes.
- Developed new systems and enhanced old processes to reduce and refine maintenance systems leading to less vehicle downtime and greater vehicle roadway compliance.

# Letterkenny Army Depot: Industrial Engineer

March 2021 - August 2021

- Created and monitored a project timeline utilizing Microsoft Project for a multi-billion-dollar construction project spanning 6 years and building 8 industrial facilities.
- Identified all construction requirements for industrial facility construction by partnering with site lead and construction foreman and ensure alignment with facility specifications for equipment and planned usage.

- Utilized CAMS and ECC, enterprise resource planning programs to develop industrial manufacturing bills of material, routes, process procedures, assembly line process, and project lead times.

### **SUNY Upstate Medical University: Project Engineer**

September 2015 - May 2016

- Utilized C++ with Arduino and micro controllers to process data, send results, display results and functions, and communicate medical information related to blood pressure.
- Created a time based algorithm to save data continuously in a fixed length array that translated 3-dimensional coordinates into a sinusoidal wave function.
- Utilized LabVIEW to test inputs and outputs of an accelerometer, pulse oximeter, and pressure sensor to calibrate and test prototype devices for reading continuous blood pressure.
- Mastered complex mathematical functions within C++ to calculate a time delay difference between the largest value of two arrays generated by axillary inputs that were constantly changing.

### **Certifications:**

Six Sigma Green Belt: ISSAC 2018

**Project Management Professional:** PMI 2020

### **Developer Skills:**

Python	JavaScript	HTML	CSS	C++
Linux	Pop!_OS	Ubuntu	BASH	Partitioning
VS Code	Git	GitHub	Version Control	Data Structures
jQuery	REACT	JSX	HTTP	AJAX
AXIOS	FLASK	State Variables	Global Variables	MongoDB
SQL	API	Bootstrap		

### **Skills:**

AutoCAD	Inventor	LabVIEW	LMP	ECC
CAMS	Microsoft Project	Auditing	Collaboration	Communication
Data Science	Fishbone	Gantt	Optimization	Presenting
Prioritization	Compliance	Scheduling	Standardization	SOPs
Development	Engagement	Design	Leadership	Execution
Innovation	Planning	Metrics	Lean Concepts	Agile Concepts

### **Education:**

**Syracuse University:** Bachelors of Science in Biomedical Engineering - 2016

Maneuver Support Center of Excellence: Engineering Project Management - 2018

San Diego State University: Full Stack Web Development - 2022 San Diego State University: M.S. Software Engineering - Current